Kareem Daley

Science Teacher

Contact

Address

Hempstead, NY, 11550

Phone

516 514 4458

E-mail

kareemtdaley@gmail.com

Skills

Student records management

Excellent

Group and individual instruction

Very Good

Testing and grading

Excellent

Standardized Testing

Excellent

Academic advisement

Very Good

Online classroom management

Excellent

Lab equipment operation

Very Good

Highly qualified Math and Science Teacher with 10 Years of experience teaching general science, chemistry, physics, biology and math up to calculus to pupils at every academic level. Plans and delivers math and science programs that includes demonstrations, lectures, discussion and student experiments to develop language, logic and problem-solving skills in classroom.

Work History

2016-09 -Current

Math/Science Teacher

C2 Education, Carl Place, New York

- Teaches chemistry, physics, biology and calculus to small classes on information compiled from multiple sources, including textbooks, online sites and other educational materials.
- Assesses student comprehension through regular quizzes, tests and assignments.
- Uses diversified teaching techniques and learning tools to help students with differing ability levels and varied learning modalities.
- Leverage diverse learning strategies to prepare students for higher-level education requirements.
- Communicates with students and parents regarding academic progress, assignments and behavior.

2016-09 -2017-03

Chemist

Farmingdale State College, Farmingdale, New York

- Assisted with researching the potential of Liquid flow batteries.
- Performed standardized tests on organic and inorganic compounds to observe fundamental differences in properties.
- Cleaned and organized laboratory and kept supplies well-stocked to save time, money and promote laboratory efficiency.
- Performed technical laboratory functions in compliance with regulatory agencies and safety requirements.

2015-08 -2016-09

Education Coordinator

Huntington Learning Center, Plainview, New York

Lesson plan development

Excellent

Research background

Very Good

Curriculum Development

Excellent

- Conducted conferences with parents and students to review progress, adjust academic plans and renew enrollments.
- Planned, formulated and assessed goals, policies and activities designed to implement educational objectives and performance standards.
- Assisted with marketing, advertising, PR and student and faculty outreach efforts to drive S.T.E.M. education program growth.
- Led planning and achievement of goals and objectives consistent with agency mission and philosophy.

2013-09 -2015-08

Teacher's Assistant

St John's University Queens Campus, Jamaica, NY

- Kept classrooms clean, neat and properly sanitized for student health and classroom efficiency.
- Reviewed lesson material with students individually or in small groups.
- Supported instructor with test administration, curriculum development and assignment grading.

Education

2018-09 -	MBA: Public Health
2019-06	Touro College - New York, NY
2010-09 -	Bachelor of Science: Chemistry
2015-06	St. John's University - Jamaica, NY